I love him!
I'm in love with Senpai.
2.5-Dimensional Ririsa
I've been in love with him since the day we met,
for the past ten years.
You're in love with...
Oh, wow, okay!
Yeah, I assumed you hadn't noticed.
And I've been spending so much time with Senpai...
When I should've known...
This is the worst thing I could've done.
Why did I tell her?
I knew if I told her the truth,
she'd change the way she acts.
And if that happens,
there's no way I'll ever make
things work with Senpai.
I've ruined everything.
I get to go to Summer Comiket
with friends in a group cosplay!
I'm so sorry. I'll stop spending so much-
Stop!
Please.
Just pretend I didn't say anything.
I don't like him.
I made it all up, okay?!
No!
Senpai taught me that real otaku never
judge someone by the things they love.
Pretend I didn't say anything.
Just tell me more about how you feel.
And why should I tell you?!
Because I want to know more about you!
About why you love him.
I guess I like how the shape of
his eyes makes him look mean.
I like that he's tall,
but I liked him when he was short, too.
I like how round the back of his head is.
I like how he looks straight into your eyes.
How he'll risk everything to help someone else.
Senpai will give his whole heart to others,
but he'll never notice when
other people do the same for him.
It's like he's intentionally blocking it out.
He's stuck where he was when he
stopped trusting women as a kid.
He was the same way when I met him.
What?!
You sure do know a lot about him, Mikari-chan.
Well, yeah, I've been watching him for ten years.
Because you love him a whole lot!
I wasn't doing it because I loved him.
I was looking for reasons to hate him,
so I could finally forget him.
Loving him hurts, you know?
I wanted to deny it.
A few good memories shouldn't
make up for how crappy he is.
I wanted to forget him so badly that
I started making a whole
list of reasons to hate him.
But that list came up empty?
Please. Just the opposite.
I came up with tons of reasons.
My list was so long.
He's a weirdo otaku, totally emotionally stunted...
Even when I thought I'd found them all,
he still gave me reasons to hate him!
But, even knowing all that,
I still couldn't stop loving him.
I couldn't even deny it.
Heartbreaking, isn't it?
Loving someone can break your heart?
Your turn now.
I asked you this before. How do you feel?
I love Senpai.
Didn't even hesitate.
I don't know if it's the same way you feel, but...
But, I understand why you like him so much!
He's so great!
I love his mean eyes,
his height, the back of his head, too!
I wanna gush about all the things
I like about him, too!
You're so weird.
He's not some manga
character you can fangirl over.
I don't see the difference!
Person or manga character, animals,
trains, whatever, the love is all the same.
If it wasn't,
then Senpai's love for Liliel wouldn't be real,
when I know it is.
Senpai is a good person.
I'll be there for you!
I'll be right there, rooting for you!
Senpai came into my life and made it better.
I'm a cosplayer.
My life as a cosplayer doesn't
exist without Senpai.
I wouldn't exist without him.
That's how much he means to me.
I don't know if that means I'm in love with him,
but I know that I love him.
So, uh, what do you think?!
You sure do love him a lot.
Weirdly, I'm happy to hear that.
We're Senpai otaku!
Don't go there.
We've gotta gush more about him together!
Huh?!
Apparently, I never wanted to get rid of my rivals.
I just wanted a friend
I could open up to about my feelings.
And Ririsa...
...is my friend.
Ririsa.
If you ever decide you want to date Senpai,
don't worry about me.
What, but...
Okay. Sure.
Thanks.
Mikari is in love with me?
How the hell did I not notice?!
It's...
It's gotta be different from how Ririsa feels.
She loves me like I love Liliel,
like I used to like other girls...
Like...
I'm sorry.
I have no idea how this is gonna go from here...
But what if she asks me out?
What if she asks me to be her boyfriend?
I'd have to say no, because I don't...
I don't like her like that.
This is horrible.
Why would I have to do
something that horrible to her?
I could ask to stay friends,
but how would that work?
Wouldn't it be awkward?
Mikari might stop coming to club.
Maybe I should just quit, then?
But, that wouldn't make anyone happy!
What should I...
ALSO HEARD
Sensei?
W-wanna talk about this?
What should I even do?
Dunno if I can tell you.
It depends on how Mikari feels,
what she does, and how you feel.
What are you scared of?
The fact that you'll have to reject
her if she asks you out?
Or the fact that doing that would ruin
your relationship with Mikari and the club?
It could be both.
Honestly, I dunno.
I never imagined what I'd do in this kind of situation.
What would you do, Sensei?
Sensei...
Have you ever been in love?
Is that what you think of me?!
I never had a love life, being a huge otaku.
But, I thought about it a whole lot.
Before, I thought it was stupid to go on dates,
or to keep asking someone out.
Like, I thought life was like a dating sim,
Wow, we keep seeing each other!
This must be destiny!
where the more you talk to someone,
the more you level up their relationship,
until asking them out finally works.
And if that didn't work,
then they were never an option in the first place.
Onii-chan!
little sister
then they were never an option in the first place.
older woman
little sister
NOT AN OPTION
I mean, in manga and anime,
all the couples are already in love with each other,
and the big confession scene is like a magic
spell that makes them realize it's mutual.
Yeah.
The problem, though,
is it convinces you it's not worth dating
someone unless they're "The One."
But, that's not how it works in real life.
Some people start dating someone even though
they might not feel anything towards them.
Some people think, "if you're gonna keep asking me out,
I might as well give you a chance."
Sorry, let me figure out what I'm trying to say.
It's okay to start dating someone even if
you don't like them that way just yet.
Getting asked out might be the first time
you realize someone likes you that way.
That's when you ask yourself how you feel about them.
Like wow, I can be myself around them,
or I'm always stealing glances at them.
I miss them when they're gone.
Maybe that means I like them?
You might start finding new things about
them that make you start to feel differently.
Love is complicated.
You might find "The One."
You might suddenly realize you're in love.
Or, you might start falling for
someone after you start dating.
Actively searching for reasons to fall
in love someone is totally valid, too.
Sorry if that didn't make any sense.
Do you at least see my point?
I don't have to end my friendship with Mikari
just because I don't
like her that way right now.
Now that I know how she feels,
I might see her differently,
and start feeling differently, too.
Damn, A+ for listening comprehension.
I don't know if I will.
I haven't felt that way about
a girl for a really long time.
I might not know why you
don't feel anything for real girls,
or what might've happened in
your past to make you feel that way.
But, I know you've had a lot
of new experiences this year.
And you've spent a lot of them with
the girls you've always wanted to avoid.
How do you feel about the 3D world now?
I know there are parts of reality that really suck,
but there are some parts worth living for.
I can't tell you which parts those are, though.
So, is it still impossible for you to trust women?
I...
Okumura.
You're good at creating close
relationships with other people.
You're not afraid to risk everything
to help someone you care about.
But it's okay to let people help you, too.
Don't be afraid to let people in.
Relationships are a two-way street.
It takes two people to make something meaningful.
That make sense?
It takes two...
In my opinion,
there's one thing you get wrong about Liliel.
Huh?
Ashford-sama!
Liliel isn't loyal because she's an angel.
She's loyal because she wants to be, for Ashford.
Believe it or not,
someone could feel that way about you, Okumura.
Really?
Someone would feel that way about me?
The same way Liliel feels about Ashford?
Wow.
So that's why I never caught onto Mikari's feelings.
Because I never saw myself as a character in my world.
I only see everyone else.
I've never asked myself
what they might think about me.
I love you.
Mom... Was that a lie?
I didn't want to feel betrayed again.
I was so terrified of going through that again,
I ignored all the signs that people cared about me.
When in reality, I... I've been...
Let me ask again.
Is it still impossible for you to trust women?
No.
It's okay if you still only trust your 2D Liliel.
But, there's a difference between
not seeing and choosing not to see.
You can open your eyes, Okumura.
Angels exist in the 3D world, too.
Okay.
Feel a little better after that?
Yeah, thank you.
But, I still don't know what I'll do about Mikari.
Yeah, that's okay.
What now? Want to just leave?
No way! We have to finish our training arc!
Right! I finally understand why
I liked those moments so much.
I've only ever seen them as
subjects through the camera.
I've never thought about how
they might be looking at me.
That's why I couldn't figure it out.
They smiled or frowned
because they were looking at me.
It was all because of me.
That's why I'm the only person
who can get those photos!
Looks like you made a breakthrough.
I think I can bust down that mental wall now.
I have to open my eyes.
I don't want to reject Mikari without
seeing her for who she really is.
I can do that if I break down that wall.
I'm not just doing this for Ririsa's dream.
I'm doing this for Mikari, and myself.
I'm not leaving until I see this through to the end!
Hey, girls, Okumura's up!
Let's get back to work!
Whoa, what's up?
Mikarin won't come out from under her blanket.
Mikari-chan...
Crying ruined my makeup
and made my eyes all puffy!
I can't let him see me like this!
I know, but...
Forget about me and go finish the shoot!
I don't wanna get in the way of you and Senpai
making your lovey-dovey cosrom, okay?
Okay.
Sorry about that.
How's Mikari?
Uh...
Mikari!
Senpai?! W-what is it?
I hope I get to take pictures of you again soon!
Ririsa.
Yes?
I want to try something new.
I realized it's not the camera
settings that make a good photo,
it's the timing of when I take it.
I always try to pick the moment where
I feel you look just like the real Liliel.
But, then I thought how your Liliel was
different from Xiaoyu's,
not in a bad way, just different.
You're the 3D person that brings the 2D Liliel to life.
I need you to see our 2.5D angel.
So now, I want to try to capture your specific Liliel.
That's my plan for today.
My specific Liliel...
I was just thinking the same thing!
No matter how badly I might want
to transform into Liliel,
I can't erase myself completely.
I thought the perfect cosplay was one where
you couldn't see the cosplayer beneath it,
but now, it's time to try something different.
I want to exist in the same space as Liliel.
Could we sit this one out and just watch?
Huh?!
This is way too advanced for me.
The whole reason we're here is
to help with your cosrom.
It's easier to do solo pics, too.
Plus, I want to see how they come out!
Yeah! Just focus on Liliel!
Ready, Liliel?!
I'm ready!
Open your eyes! Do this for Mikari! For Ririsa!
For everyone who cares about me!
I'm not recreating the source.
I'm creating my own Liliel.
What aspects do we both share?
How does she feel? How do I feel?
Ashford-sama, I love you!
I can't! I have to keep these feelings to myself!
Senpai promised he wouldn't fall for
me so we could be cosplay partners.
It wouldn't be fair for me to fall for him.
I don't know if it's the same way you feel, but...
That was a lie.
I thought I was telling Mikari-chan the truth.
Maybe I don't like him as just a friend.
But I lied to myself.
I already know how I feel.
It's more than that.
Liliel...
Senpai will never feel anything for me.
Wear all the sexy outfits you want,
I guarantee you I won't feel a thing for you!
I'll never have him. That's why this is okay.
That's why, right now,
I can let out some of the feelings
I've been holding back for so long.
Ashford-sama, I love you!
Not yet...
I need to see the Ririsa inside Liliel!
Senpai, I love you.
Man, I can't believe summer break's almost over.
Let's all take a picture together!
Can I post this one online?
feeling better
No thanks.
I'm scared of your side of social media.
My contract says I can't.
Not if we're not cosplaying...
You sure you guys are teenagers?
I don't mind.
Yay! Lemme get one with you!
Never mind. People might think we're dating.
Really?
I want a picture with you, Senpai!
Wait, I thought you just said you can't!
Oh, right. She wants to take a picture with me.
That's kinda cute.
Wait, what did I just think?
How'd your training arc turn out?
I think I know what you mean now
about relationships being a two-way street.
I lived my whole life assuming no
one had cared about me at all.
But, now I know people do care.
They have thoughts and opinions about me.
So of course they have feelings about me, too.
It's the first time I've ever realized...
I actually exist as something in other people's lives.
HMM?
That's it?
I mean, I guess going from nothing to
something is progress, but still...
When's he gonna realize that he means
Are you done staring at those pictures yet?
everything to some of the people around him?
Ack, sorry! Here!
Y'know...
That's a pretty good picture.
Noa! You're going to be late for school!
Eating in the clubroom today!
Managed to snag these before they were gone!!
Can't wait to be there with you
Feels like that's my actual school
What's that mean?
Nono-pi!
Let's walk together!
Hey, girls! Always love your energy. Have fun!
We will!
MOM
same as always
What's for dinner?
Sorry, I'm going out
with Dad tonight!
Have funnn
Nono-pi, we should all go out to dinner tonight!
I'm in!
Aria-chan, Nonoa-chan!
Detention again?
Sorry for the delay, Senpai!
There you are.
Ooh, is it ready?!
What's ready?
Liliel: Side Story, Okumura's Cut!
You made this?
Sure did! Figured it'd inspire your next project.
I can't wait to watch it!
Here it comes!
Wait, I'm doing this, too?
Ready, go!
Liliel!
SEASON TWO CONFIRMED!!